Brian Bollen

A Current Ph.D. student in Applied Mathematics who has strong background in research in mathematics and computer science, developing web and mobile applications, and 3+ years of teaching at the University of Arizona under his belt.

■ bbollen23@gmail.com

(315) 507-0131

lin

linkedin.com/in/brian-bollen-a3123484

EDUCATION

PhD in Applied Mathematics

May 2022 (Expected) Tucson, AZ

B.S. in Mathematics, Minor in Computer Science

August 2013 - May 2017 Albanv, NY

University at Albany

University of Arizona

GPA: 3.83

TECHNICAL SKILLS

D3.js HTML Python React CSS Javascript React-Native Node.js Express.js GraphQL MongoDB) SQL

RESEARCH

Research Assistant

September 2018 - Present Tucson, AZ

University of Arizona

Currently working with Professor Joshua Levine of the Computer Science department at the University of Arizona, Our research is focused on the study, design, and implementation of similarity metrics for topological structures to aid in the analysis of multifaceted scalar fields. While our research is rooted in mathematical theory which has been created by other researchers, our main focus is on the application of these metrics. In addition, we are interested in leveraging machine learning techniques to (1) create similarity metrics through supervised training and (2) aid in the computation of computationally complex metrics such as interleaving distance and functional distortion distance on Reeb graphs.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Co-Founder

June 2020 - Present Tucson, AZ

TutorYard. Inc.

Co-Founded a Tucson-based Tutoring company which hires graduate and undergraduate students to tutor students privately and through local charter/private schools.

Personally focused on developing and maintaining a website where users were able to find and book tutors smoothly.

Developing software for charter schools where administrators and teachers are able to view analytics of all students we are tutoring based on effective data tracking by our tutors.

Teaching Assistant

September 2017 - May 2020

University of Arizona

Tucson, AZ

Taught mathematics at the university level for courses including Pre-Calculus and Calculus for seven semesters.

OTHER PROJECTS

MuView: Music Review Visualization for Exploratory Analysis

September 2019 - Present

Currently designing and implementing a visualization of Music review data from various publications to provide users with a more full, exploratory experience when searching for new albums to listen to. Current implementation uses a combination of D3.js and React.js with Redux to provide a visual interactive tool of review data from 2018.